A Guide to the Virginia Dept. of Military Affairs, Adjutant General Interwar unit files, 1918-1941
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Records of the Virginia Dept. of Military Affairs, Adjutant General Interwar unit files, 1918-1941
The Library of Virginia
32443
15 cu.ft. (33 boxes and 1 oversize folder)
Virginia. Dept. of Military Affairs.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred on 29 July 1985 by the Dept. of Military Affairs, Historical Section, 501 E. Franklin Street, Richmond, Virginia, 23219. Only boxes 13-20 were transferred from the Adjutant General's Office.
Historical Information
During the First World War, the units from Virginia joined units from Maryland and the District of Columbia to form the 29th Division. Following the war, the Virginia National Guard consisted of the following units: 91st Infantry Brigade; 116th Infantry; 183rd Infantry; 111th Field Artillery; Ambulance Battalion Headquarters, 104th Medical Regiment; Ambulance Co. No. 110; Hospital Co. No. 110; Medical Support Section No. 104; Medical Laboratory Section No. 104; 29th Signal Company; 29th Tank Company; 167th Engineer Battalion; Co. B, 111th Military Police Battalion; and 16th Service Battalion.
Between 1918 and 1922, numerous changes took place in the Virginia National Guard. The 1st and 2nd Infantry were redesignated by the War Department as the 183rd and 116th Infantry, respectively. The 1st Brigade became the 91st Brigade. The 1st Coast Defense Command of the Coast Artillery Corps was redesignated as the 246th Artillery and the units of that regiment including the 411th through 415th Companies Coast Artillery Corps were redesignated Batteries A through H of the 246th Artillery.
Scope and Content
Records, 1918-1941, consisting of interwar unit files of Virginia's National Guard from the Adjutant General's office. The files were created between World War I and World War II (interwar). Includes correspondence, clippings, orders, payrolls, reports, service records, and telegrams, among others. Includes officer service records, discharge orders, special orders, summary courts martial records, officer resignations, officer efficiency reports, retirements, payrolls, monthly drill reports, investigations, reports of training, inspections, reports of armory break-in & fires, state military reservation material, aid to civil authority, unit files, and other miscellaneous records. Includes files relating to the 1st Infantry Regiment, 29th Tank Company, 54th Field Artillery, 104th Medical Regiment, 111th Field Artillery, 116th Infantry, 246th Coast Artillery, and 415th Coast Artillery.
One of the largest groupings are the Summary Courts Martial Records, which are arranged alphabetically by last name of soldier. The records mainly consist of charge sheets including the soldiers names, enlistment, charges, affidavits, pleas, and findings. Most of the charges relate to missing drills and training (absence without leave). Included are retirement files which contain detailed soldier service histories; orders relating to horses used, including physical descriptions of the horses and noting any injuries or deaths of horses; orders and reports detailing ordnance and military equipment (guns, tanks, trucks); and inquiries from towns requesting the creation of local National Guard units.
The Aid to Civil Authority includes instances where the National Guard was sent to cities or towns to help fight forest fires, clean up after storms, or to break up protestors or strikers (such as the Dan River Cotton Mills, Danville, Va., 1930 and Bonus Marchers, 1934). Also of note are the history and heraldy papers that contain information on the history of various units. The Officer Service Records include correspondence detailing officers military service and some questionnaires detailing birth, service, military academy graduation, current address and occupation.
The files are arranged numerically by a file number assigned by the Adjutant General's office. An inventory in the Manuscript Room represents more than what is included in this accession. Only boxes 13-20 were transferred from the Adjutant General's Office.
Arrangement
The original order was maintained for the collection and is arranged by file number. Files 216-217 are at the end of the collection due to the fact that they weren't identified until processing was almost complete.
Contents List
- Discharge orders, 246th Coast Artillery, Headquarters Battery [File 362], 1938-1940 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Discharge orders, 246th Coast Artillery, Band Section [File 363], 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Discharge orders, 246th Coast Artillery, Medical Department Detachment [File 364], 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Discharge orders, 246th Coast Artillery, Battery A [File 365], 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Discharge orders, 246th Coast Artillery, Battery B [File 366], 1936-1939 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Discharge orders, 246th Coast Artillery, Battery C [File 367], 1937-1939 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Discharge orders, 246th Coast Artillery, Battery D [File 368], 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Discharge orders, 246th Coast Artillery, Battery E [File 369], 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Discharge orders, 246th Coast Artillery, Battery F [File 370], 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Discharge orders, 246th Coast Artillery, Battery G [File 371], 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Discharge orders, 246th Coast Artillery, Battery H [File 372], 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Special orders, 104th Medical Regiment [File 373], 1938-1942 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Special orders, 104th Medical Regiment, Company D [File 374], 1922-1940 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Discharge orders, 104th Medical Regiment, Company D [File 375], 1936-1941 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Special orders, 104th Medical Regiment, Company G [File 376], 1921-1940 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Discharge orders, 104th Medical Regiment, Company G [File 377], 1936-1940 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Special orders, 104th Medical Battalion [File 378], 1942 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Special orders, 104th Quartermaster Regiment [File 379], 1937-1941 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Discharge orders, 104th Quartermaster Regiment, Company C [File 380], 1936-1940 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Discharge orders, 104th Quartermaster Regiment, Company F [File 381], 1940 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Orders, 91st Infantry Brigade [File 382], 1922-1941 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Discharge orders, 91st Infantry Brigade, Headquarters Company [File 383], 1936-1940 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Orders, 54th Field Artillery Brigade [File 384], 1936-1941 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Discharge orders, 54th Field Artillery Brigade, Headquarters Battery [File 385], 1938-1940 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Orders, 29th Tank Company [File 386], 1921-1941 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Discharge orders, 29th Tank Company [File 387], 1936-1941 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Orders, 29th Signal Company [File 388], 1924-1941 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Discharge orders, 29th Signal Company [File 389], 1936-1940 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Orders, State Camps [File 390], 1922-1940 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous transfer orders [File 391], 1926-1938 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Transfer orders, Miscellaneous units [File 392], 1938-1940 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Miscellaneous discharge orders [File 393], 1932 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Discharge orders, National Guard Reserves [File 394], 1931 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Discharge orders, State detachment [File 395], 1936-1940 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Discharge orders, Naval Militia [File 396], 1931 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Discharge orders, John Marshall High School Cadet Corps [File 397], 1929 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, Acree-Ayscue [File 398], 1921-1931 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, Babb-Bayne [File 399], 1921-1931 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, Beal-Bishop [File 399], 1921-1931 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, Blackmon-Boykins [File 400], 1921-1931 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, Bradley-Bryant [File 400], 1921-1931 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, Buchanan-Byrd [File 400], 1921-1931 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, Cadmus-Chilton [File 401], 1921-1931 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, Clark-Covington [File 401], 1921-1931 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, Craig-Cutchins [File 401], 1921-1931 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, Dahn-Dillon [File 402], 1921-1931 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, Dobbs-Doyle [File 402], 1921-1931 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, Draper-Duty [File 402], 1921-1931 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, Eanes-Evans [File 403], 1921-1931 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, Falwell-Floyd [File 404], 1921-1931 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, Ford-Fox [File 404], 1921-1931 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, Francis-Fuqua [File 404], 1921-1931 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, Gardner-Gilman [File 405], 1921-1931 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, Goad-Gwin [File 405], 1921-1931 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, Hagy-Harlow [File 406], 1921-1931 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, Harmon-Hays [File 406], 1921-1931 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, Hedgepeth-Hite [File 406], 1921-1931 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, Hobson-Hoyle [File 407], 1921-1931 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, Hubbard-Hydapool [File 407], 1921-1931 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, I [File 408], 1921-1931 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, Jackson-Justis [File 409], 1921-1931 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, Kahle-Kurka [File 410], 1921-1931 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, Lambert-Lawrence [File 411], 1921-1931 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, Leake-Lewis [File 411], 1921-1931 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, Lindsey-Lynch [File 411], 1921-1931 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, McCartney-McQuarters [File 412], 1921-1931 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, Mallory-Mitchell [File 412], 1921-1931 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, Moon-Myers [File 412], 1921-1931 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, N [File 413], 1921-1931 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, O [File 414], 1921-1931 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, Page-Pauli [File 415], 1921-1931 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, Pearson-Pittman [File 415], 1921-1931 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, Pond-Puryear [File 415], 1921-1931 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, Q [File 416], 1921-1931 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, Radcliffe-Riner [File 417], 1921-1931 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, Roache-Rust [File 417], 1921-1931 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, Sack-Seymour [File 418], 1921-1931 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, Shackelford-Shumate [File 418], 1921-1931 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, Silvey-Slayden [File 418], 1921-1931 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, Smith-Spruill [File 418], 1921-1931 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, St. Clair-Swift [File 418], 1921-1931 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, Talbott-Terek [File 419], 1921-1931 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, Thomas-Turner [File 419], 1921-1931 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, Updike-Von Toney [File 420], 1921-1931 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, Wade-Watts [File 421], 1921-1931 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, Webber-Whorley [File 421], 1921-1931 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, Wickings-Wingfield [File 421], 1921-1931 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, Wolfman-Wyatt [File 421], 1921-1931 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, Y [File 422], 1921-1931 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Summary Courts Martial Records, Z [File 423], 1921-1931 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Officer Resignations [File 424], 1919-1923 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Officer Resignations [File 424], 1919-1924 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Officer Resignations [File 424], 1920-1924 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Officer Resignations [File 424], 1925-1929 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Officer Resignations [File 424], 1926-1930 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Officer Resignations [File 424], 1934-1937 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Retired Office Statement of Service [File 425], 1920 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Officer Efficiency Reports [File 426], 1919-1921 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Officer Efficiency Reports [File 426], 1921 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Officer Efficiency Reports [File 426], 1923 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Officer Efficiency Reports [File 426], 1925 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Officer Efficiency Reports [File 427], 1925-1927 (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Officer Efficiency Reports [File 427], 1927-1928 (Box 12, Folder 8-9)
- Officer Efficiency Reports [File 428], 1926-1928 (Box 13, Folder 1-3)
- Retirement of Cecil C. Vaughan [File 429], 1919 (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Retirement of T.M. Wortham [File 430], 1919 (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Retirement of J. Meek Wolf [File 431], 1919 (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Retirement of William J. Perry [File 432], 1919 (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Retirement of C.C. Moss [File 433], 1918-1919 (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Retirement of Charles F. Krause [File 434], 1919 (Box 13, Folder 9)
- Retirement of John A. Cutchins [File 435], 1919 (Box 13, Folder 10)
- Retirement of C.H. Causey [File 436], 1918-1919 (Box 13, Folder 11)
- Retirement of Joshua F. Bullitt [File 437], 1919 (Box 13, Folder 12)
- Retirement of Alvah B. Cousins [File 438], 1920 (Box 13, Folder 13)
- Retirement of John R. Kerrick [File 439], 1919-1920 (Box 13, Folder 14)
- Retirement of Clifton C. Moore [File 440], 1919-1920 (Box 13, Folder 15)
- Retirement of Leroy F. Vaughan [File 441], 1920 (Box 13, Folder 16)
- Retirement of Aurelius W. Bohannon [File 442], 1921 (Box 13, Folder 17)
- Retirement of George M. Bell [File 443], 1921 (Box 13, Folder 18)
- Retirement of Paul F. Newell [File 444], 1921 (Box 13, Folder 19)
- Retirement of Edward J. Keegan [File 445], 1922 (Box 13, Folder 20)
- Retirement of Emmit D. Butts [File 446], 1919-1921 (Box 13, Folder 21)
- Retirement of William M. Evans [File 447], 1922 (Box 13, Folder 22)
- Retirement of Jo. Lane Stern [File 448], 1922 (Box 13, Folder 23)
- Retirement of Robert T. Barton [File 449], 1928 (Box 13, Folder 24)
- Retirement of Ellis Mann [File 450], 1932 (Box 13, Folder 25)
- Retirement of George W. Booker [File 451], 1933 (Box 13, Folder 26)
- Retirement of Harry C. Bailey [File 452], 1935 (Box 13, Folder 27)
- Payrolls, State Quartermaster Staff [File 453], 1919-1920 (Box 13, Folder 28)
- Payrolls, State Staff [File 454], 1920-1927 (Box 13, Folder 29)
- Payrolls, State Staff [File 454], 1923-1929 (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Payrolls, 29th Division Staff [File 455], 1923-1929 (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Payrolls, 116th Infantry, Company M [File 456], 1927 (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Payrolls, 246th Coast Artillery, Band Section [File 457], 1929 (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Payrolls, 1st Infantry, Hospital Corps [File 458], 1921 (Box 14, Folder 5)
- List of Employees, Adjutant General's Office [File 459], 1860-1919 (Box 14, Folder 6)
- Case of pardon for Henry P. Whitsell [File 460], 1936 (Box 14, Folder 7)
- Case on injury to Gayle McGuire Turner [File 461], 1928-1932 (Box 14, Folder 8)
- Death of John Mason [File 462], 1930 (Box 14, Folder 9)
- Death of Nicholas B. Stamos [File 463], 1932-1934 (Box 14, Folder 10)
- Death of Eugene G. Riner [File 463], 1932 (Box 14, Folder 11)
- Death of Wilton N. Rice [File 464], 1934 (Box 14, Folder 12)
- Death of Robert H. Lum [File 465], 1934 (Box 14, Folder 13)
- Death of Robert E. Hawkins [File 466], 1934 (Box 14, Folder 14)
- Death of Robert E. Bond [File 467], 1935 (Box 14, Folder 15)
- Death of Ellis L. Berger [File 468], 1935 (Box 14, Folder 16)
- Death of Guy R. Kabrich [File 469], 1935 (Box 14, Folder 17)
- Death of William H. James [File 470], 1935 (Box 14, Folder 18)
- Investigation of Harry Lee Keeton [File 471], 1935-1936 (Box 14, Folder 19)
- Investigation of Henry G. Dickerson [File 472], 1922 (Box 14, Folder 20)
- Investigation of Samuel L. Cohen [File 473], 1919 (Box 14, Folder 21)
- Report of Efficiency Board, Lt. James Perry [File 474], 1931-1932 (Box 14, Folder 22)
- Citation for Bravery, Sgt. James W. Dyer [File 475], 1933-1934 (Box 15, Folder 1)
- State Distinguished Service Medals [File 476], 1922-1937 (Box 15, Folder 2)
- Assorted Personnel Dispositions, Misc. [File 477], 1919-1924 (Box 15, Folder 3)
- Materials pertaining to the disposition of horses upon mechanization [File 478], 1933-1934 (Box 15, Folder 4)
- 111th Field Artillery, General, Horses [File 479], 1926-1933 (Box 15, Folder 5)
- 111th Field Artillery, Headquarters Battery, Horses [File 480], 1925-1934 (Box 15, Folder 6)
- 111th Field Artillery, Service Battery, Horses [File 481], 1929-1934 (Box 15, Folder 7)
- 111th Field Artillery, Battery A, Horses [File 482], 1921-1934 (Box 15, Folder 8)
- 111th Field Artillery, Battery B, Horses [File 483], 1925-1933 (Box 15, Folder 9)
- 111th Field Artillery, Battery C, Horses [File 484], 1926-1934 (Box 15, Folder 10)
- 111th Field Artillery, Battery D, Horses [File 485], 1925-1934 (Box 15, Folder 11)
- 111th Field Artillery, Battery E, Horses [File 486], 1926-1934 (Box 15, Folder 12)
- 111th Field Artillery, Battery F, Horses [File 487], 1926-1934 (Box 16, Folder 1)
- 29th Signal Company, Horses [File 488], 1925 (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Mules [File 489], 1921-1934 (Box 16, Folder 3)
- Materials pertaining to automobiles [File 490], 1933-1934 (Box 16, Folder 4)
- Materials pertaining to motorcycles [File 491], 1921 (Box 16, Folder 5)
- Materials pertaining to ambulances [File 492], 1934-1936 (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Materials pertaining to trucks [File 493], 1924-1937 (Box 16, Folder 7)
- Materials pertaining to artillery trucks [File 494], 1926-1930 (Box 16, Folder 8)
- Materials pertaining to military trailors [File 495], 1931-1935 (Box 16, Folder 9)
- Materials pertaining to tanks [File 496], 1930-1937 (Box 16, Folder 10)
- Materials pertaining to the mechanization of the 111th Field Artillery [File 497], 1930-1935 (Box 16, Folder 11)
- Materials pertaining to the mechanization of the 29th Signal Company [File 498], 1930-1935 (Box 16, Folder 12)
- Materials pertaining to aircrafts and airfields [File 499], 1921-1936 (Box 16, Folder 13)
- Reports on ordnance [File 500], 1927-1928 (Box 16, Folder 14-16)
- Materials pertaining to ordnance [File 501], 1933-1937 (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Materials pertaining to Thompson Sub-Machine Guns [File 502], 1928 (Box 17, Folder 2)
- Military drill reports, 1st Regiment [File 503], 1919-1922 (Box 17, Folder 3)
- Military drill reports, Adjutant General [File 503], 1921-1922 (Box 17, Folder 4)
- Military drill reports, Arsenal [File 503], 1921-1922 (Box 17, Folder 5)
- Military drill reports, Edwin P. Conquest [File 503], 1921-1922 (Box 17, Folder 6)
- Military drill reports, J.A.G.D. [File 503], 1920-1922 (Box 17, Folder 7)
- Military drill reports, Machine Gun Company [File 503], 1918-1921 (Box 17, Folder 8)
- Military drill reports, Ordnance Dept. [File 503], 1920-1922 (Box 17, Folder 9)
- Military drill reports, Quartermaster Corps [File 503], 1920-1922 (Box 17, Folder 10)
- Military drill reports, Separate Company [File 503], 1919-1921 (Box 17, Folder 11)
- Military drill reports, State Headquarters [File 503], 1921-1922 (Box 17, Folder 12)
- Military drill reports, State Staff Corps and Depts. [File 503], 1919-19622 (Box 17, Folder 13)
- Military drill reports, Veterinary Corps [File 503], 1921-1922 (Box 17, Folder 14)
- Misc. pay rolls [File 504], 1920-1936 (Box 17, Folder 15)
- Reports of training [File 505], 1919-1920 (Box 17, Folder 16)
- Reports of training [File 506], 1921 (Box 18, Folder 1)
- Reports of training [File 507], 1922 (Box 18, Folder 2)
- Reports of training [File 508], 1922-1923 (Box 18, Folder 3)
- Reports of training [File 509], 1924 (Box 18, Folder 4)
- Reports of training [File 510], 1925 (Box 18, Folder 5)
- Reports of training [File 511], 1926 (Box 18, Folder 6)
- Reports of training [File 512], 1927 (Box 18, Folder 7)
- Reports of training [File 513], 1928 (Box 18, Folder 8)
- Reports of training [File 514], 1929 (Box 18, Folder 9)
- Reports of training [File 515], 1930 (Box 19, Folder 1)
- Reports of training [File 516], 1931 (Box 19, Folder 2-3)
- Reports of training [File 517], 1932 (Box 19, Folder 4-5)
- Reports of training [File 518], 1933 (Box 19, Folder 6-7)
- Reports of training [File 519], 1934 (Box 20, Folder 1-2)
- Reports of training [File 520], 1935 (Box 20, Folder 3)
- Reports of training [File 521], 1936 (Box 20, Folder 4)
- Inspections [File 522], 1920-1921 (Box 20, Folder 5)
- Inspections, 1st Infantry [File 523], 1932 (Box 20, Folder 6)
- Inspections, 116th Infantry [File 524], 1932 (Box 20, Folder 7)
- Inspections, 111th Field Artillery [File 525], 1932 (Box 21, Folder 1)
- Inspections, 246th Coast Artillery [File 526], 1932 (Box 21, Folder 2)
- Inspections, Misc. Units [File 527], 1932 (Box 21, Folder 3)
- Reports on Status of Armories, 1st Infantry [File 528], 1926-1934 (Box 21, Folder 4)
- Reports on Status of Armories, 116th Infantry [File 529], 1922-1929 (Box 21, Folder 5)
- Reports on Status of Armories, 111th Field Artillery [File 530], 1926-1934 (Box 21, Folder 6)
- Reports on Status of Armories, 246th Coast Artillery [File 531], 1926-1934 (Box 21, Folder 7)
- Reports on Status of Armories, Separate Units [File 532], 1930-1933 (Box 21, Folder 8)
- Reports on Status of Armories, Misc. [File 533], 1922-1933 (Box 21, Folder 9)
- Materials pertaining to Naval Militia [File 534], 1919-1936 (Box 21, Folder 10)
- Materials pertaining to the Oyster State Navy [File 535], 1926-1930 (Box 22, Folder 1)
- Report of Armory break-in (Winchester) [File 536], 1926 (Box 22, Folder 2)
- Report of Armory break-in (Roanoke) [File 537], 1927 (Box 22, Folder 3)
- Report of Armory break-in (Norfolk) [File 538], 1928 (Box 22, Folder 4)
- Report of Armory break-in (Ashland) [File 539], 1928 (Box 22, Folder 5)
- Report of Armory break-in (Danville) [File 540], 1931 (Box 22, Folder 6)
- Report of Armory break-in (Christiansburg) [File 541], 1925 (Box 22, Folder 7)
- Report of Armory break-in (Hampton) [File 542], 1935 (Box 22, Folder 8)
- Report of Armory break-in (Norfolk) [File 543], 1935 (Box 22, Folder 9)
- Report of Armory break-in (Martinsburg) [File 544], 1936 (Box 22, Folder 10)
- Report of Armory break-in (Berryville) [File 545], 1935 (Box 22, Folder 11)
- Report of Armory fire (Danville) [File 546], 1926 (Box 22, Folder 12)
- Report of Armory fire (Bedford) [File 547], 1926 (Box 22, Folder 13)
- Report of Armory fire (Hampton) [File 548], 1928 (Box 22, Folder 14)
- Report of Armory fire (Roanoke) [File 549], 1928 (Box 22, Folder 15)
- Report of Armory fire (Danville) [File 550], 1931 (Box 22, Folder 16)
- Report of Armory fire (Portsmouth) [File 551], 1932, 1936 (Box 22, Folder 17)
- European trip, Richmond Light Infantry Blues [File 552], 1926 (Box 22, Folder 18)
- Philadelphia Sesquicentennial [File 553], 1926 (Box 22, Folder 19)
- Inauguration of Govnernor Harry F. Byrd [File 554], 1926 (Box 22, Folder 20)
- Inauguration of Governor John Garland Pollard [File 555] (Box 22, Folder 21)
- Inauguration of President Herbert Hoover [File 556], 1929 (Box 22, Folder 22)
- Yorktown Commemoration [File 557], 1931-1932 (Box 22, Folder 23)
- George Washington Bicentennial Parade (Alexandria, Va.) [File 558], 1932 (Box 22, Folder 24)
- President of President Franklin D. Roosevelt [File 559], 1932-1933 (Box 22, Folder 25)